hey guys this looks like a fun one it
gives us that x * Y is = 36 and that x^2
+ y^2 is equal 78 and it wants to know
what is x 4 + y 4th if you want to try
this on your own pause it right now cuz
I'm going to solve it in 3 2 1 in order
to figure this out we don't have to
completely solve for x and y there's a
pretty cool shortcut that we can apply
let me show you let's copy down the x^2
+ y^2 = 78 and let's Square both sides
of the equation the squares mean that
we're going to have this times this
equals this time this on the right hand
side 78 * 78 is equal to
684 and on the left hand side you can
multiply this out let's use one of these
squares x^2 * x^2 = x 4 x^2 * y^2 is =
x^2 y^2 and then we have another x^2 *
y^2 so that'll be x^2 y^2 and then we
have y^2 * y^2 which is equal to Y 4 and
these insides are what we would get if
we were to multiply it out next let's
focus on this x^2 y^2 x^2 y^2 is the
same thing as xy^ 2 and then we can copy
down everything else in the place of the
XY we're going to plug in 36 and then 2
* 36 * 36 is equal to
2592 we can subtract 2592 from both
sides on the left hand side these will
cancel each other out so we're left with
X 4th + y 4th and on the right hand side
684 - 2592 is
3492 and that's the answer to our
question let's put a box around it how
exciting